Inventory of the Edward J. Rozek papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Edward J. Rozek papers
1939-2009
1970-2009
2014C58
Hoover Institution Archives
114 manuscript boxes, 36 card file boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 motion picture film reels (62.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, and audiovisual material relating to communism and to political conditions in Eastern Europe. Includes records of the Institute for the Study of Economic and Political Freedom.
Rozek, Edward J.
Institute for the Study of Economic and Political Freedom.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Born in Poland in 1918, Edward Rozek fought first for Poland and then for the Polish Tenth Armoured Brigade during World War II. Following the war, Rozek moved to the United States in 1948 and attended Harvard University, where he earned his BA, MA, and PhD. After graduating, Rozek accepted a position at the University of Colorado, where he remained a professor for his entire academic career. At the University of Colorado, Rozek founded and directed both the Edward Teller Center (later renamed the Center for Science, Technology and Political Thought) and the Institute for the Study of Economic and Political Freedom.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, writings, letters to the editor, printed matter, and audiovisual material relating to communism and to political conditions in Eastern Europe. Includes records of the Institute for the Study of Economic and Political Freedom as well as for the Center for Science, Technology and Political Thought. Of note are the materials from a prominent court case from 1978 to 1985, in which the University of Colorado sued Edward Rozek for embezzlement and misuse of Institute funds.
Communism.; Europe, Eastern--Politics and government--1945-; Motion pictures.; Audiotapes.; Video tapes.
- Personal Records, 1959-2009 (Boxes 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Personal correspondence, notes, and drafts of memoir.
  - Election, 1980 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Edward Rozek, retirement articles, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Susan E. Rozek estate, undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Beth MacParland's letters to Edward Rozek, 1979-1990 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Retirement letters, 1991 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Edward Rozek, 2009 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    Includes Polish newspaper and correspondence regarding obituaries, including information regarding Rozek's true date of birth.
  - Sympathy cards regarding Edward Rozek, 2009 (Box-folder 1: 7-8)
  - American Values Award, 1985 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Personal history, undated
    - "Childhood and Youth" (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - "Background to War" (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - "Invasion and War, 1939-1946" (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - "France, 1940" (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - "England, 1940-1944" (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - "Falaise" (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - "From Normandy to Germany" (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - "The Aristocratic Coal Miner" (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - "Emigration/Illinois" (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - "Harvard, Undergraduate/Graduate" (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - "Radio Free Europe" (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - "Marriage and Family Life" (Box-folder 1: 22)
    - "Conflicts at University of Colorado, I" (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - "Conflicts at University of Colorado II, The 1960s" (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - "Conflicts at University of Colorado III, Complications with Politics" (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - "Conflicts at University of Colorado IV, Goldwater et al." (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - William Peterson, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 1974 trip to Europe (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - 1975 trip to Taiwan (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - 1976-1980 election (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Excerpts from A Question of Honor by Lynne Olson and Stanley Cloud, undated (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Clippings, Quigg Newton controversy, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- Correspondence, 1950-2009 (Boxes 3-38)
  - Letters to join society, letters from members with dues, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Solzhenitsyn Society newspaper clippings, 1976 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Conference on Détente correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - 1977 Conference, September form letters, and agenda (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Definition of Purpose application form, undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Financial statements, Institute for the Study of Economic and Political Freedom, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 3: 6-10)
  - Buechner resignation clippings, 1999 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Wassily Leontief, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Frederic A. Wyatt fundraising, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Contributions received, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Change of name, Edward Teller Center to Center for Science, Technology and Political Thought, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Publicity, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Caspar W. Weinberger, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Documents from Edward Teller Center, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Kostka Land-Use Conference, Détente Conference, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - William Kostka & Associates, Inc., 1974 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - State of Colorado Certificate of Incorporation, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Edward Teller Center documents, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Edward Teller Center bylaws, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Dan R. Pitner, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Photographs for Teller Center brochure, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Teller Center clippings, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Brzezinski, 1979 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Carrigan letter to the Denver Post, 1978 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - General Alexander M. Haig, Jr., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Franklin controversy, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Brian Crozier, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - John Cropsey, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - J. W. Bowersock, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Dr. Bruno Bettelheim, advertisement and curriculum vitae, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Luis Alvarez, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Harold M. Agnew, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Ronald Max Hartwell, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Charles A. Fenstermacher, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - David Daube, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - John D'Arms, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Richard Wilson, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Lt. Col. Tomas G. Storey, USAF, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Hans-Peter Stahl, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Lord & Lady Michael Lindsay, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Aden B. Meinel, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Philip Crane, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Denys L. Page, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - John Scott, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Frank Shakespeare, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Hon. James C. H. Shen, Ambassador from Free China, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Marriott Hotel, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Kostka Land-Use Conference, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Détente and the Far East, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Buckley dinner, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - 1981 May 3 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Speakers, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Accuracy in Academia, 1985 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Konrad Adenauer Stiftung, 1984 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Philip Agee, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Abdul Malik Al-Sayed, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Judith Albino, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Janusz Bugajskc, 1992 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Russell Campbell, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Central America, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Chou En-Lai, 1971 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - CIA protests, University of Colorado (CU-Boulder), 1985 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Coalition for Peace Through Strength, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Cocaine, 1985 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Brian Crozier, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Defense, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Czechoslovakia (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Edward Derwinski, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Bob Ewegen, 1993-2004 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Julio Fernandez, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - John Glubb (Pasha), 1971-1976 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Documents, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Neal Groff, 1991-2001 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Rosalind Haley, 1990 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Mark Hannon (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Gary Hart, 1979 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Seymour Hersh (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Landon Hilliard, 1993 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    Lease agreement with Blair Chamberlain.
  - Alger Hiss, 1982 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Lisa Howard, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Bill Hudson, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Cal Jillson, 1989 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Pam Jewett, 1994 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Whittle Johnston, 1991 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Rex John, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Ahmad Kianpour, 1981 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Charles L. King, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Korea, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Daniel Kowalski re Roman Marzak, 1989 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - William Kristol, 2003 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - American Labor, 1978 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Frank Land, 1982 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Manning Marable, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Nanno Marinatos, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - John R. Martinez, 1999 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - James L. Marvin, 1987 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Jim Martin, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Henry Noble McCracken, 1956 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Daniel McMichael, 1977 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - William C. Mott, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Steven Miller, 1991 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Nobel Committee, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Neil C. Norgren, 1978-1994 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Sam Nunn, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Paderewski delegation, 1992 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Ozzie Paez, 1988 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Neni E. K. Panourgia, 1994 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Michael Parenti, 1988 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Philippines, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Norman Ream, 1988 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Republican Senatorial Inner Circle, 1991 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Carl Sagan, 1986 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - Frank Shakespeare, 1977 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - James Gregory Sheer (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - Reverend Michael J. Sheeran, 2002 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - Theodore Shippey, 1997 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Viseslav Simic, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Leroy Sluder, 1984 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Clyde A. Sluhan, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Clyde A. Sluhan, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 10: 4-6)
  - Solidarity, 1996 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Soviet Politico and Secretariat and Foreign Ministry, undated (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Justice Clarence Thomas, 2001 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - Harry T. Willets, 1976 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Andrew Willman, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Jack G. Wilson, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - World Anti-Communist League, 1987 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Albino controversy, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Madeleine Albright, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Joe Alexander, 2003 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Sven Alkalai, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Senator Gordon Allott, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - American Council for World Freedom, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Arthur Anderson, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Swede and Judy Anderson, 2000 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Senator John Andrews, 2001 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Anschutz Foundation, 1984 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Armored Division, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 11)
    Materials in Polish.
  - William Armstrong, 1970-2004 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - Bud Arnold, Secretary Board of Regents, University of Colorado, 1986 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Kathy Arnold, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - Arts and Sciences, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - Pete Atkins, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - Asta Banionis, 1990 (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - Sally Barclay, 1981 (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - Hazel Barnes, 2006 (Box-folder 11: 19)
  - Bartosik, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 11: 20)
    Includes letters in Polish.
  - Henryk Batowski, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 11: 21)
  - Honorable Robert C. Battersby, 1992 (Box-folder 11: 22)
  - James Beach, 1993 (Box-folder 11: 23)
  - Lord Bauer, 1985 (Box-folder 11: 24)
  - James Beach, trip to Russia, 1993 (Box-folder 11: 25)
  - Ryszard Bartosz, 1998-2005 (Box-folder 11: 26)
  - Pope Benedict XVI, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 27)
  - William Bennett, Secretary of Education, 1992 (Box-folder 11: 28)
  - Richard Bernick, 1991 (Box-folder 11: 29)
  - Alain Besancon, 1993 (Box-folder 11: 30)
  - Morton C. Blackwell, The Leadership Institute, 1988 (Box-folder 11: 31)
  - Czeslaw Bloch, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Czeslaw Bloch, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 12: 2-3)
  - Arnaud de Borchgrave, 1985 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Judge Robert Bork, 1987 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Bradley Foundation, 1970-2008 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Sir Bernard Braine, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Hudson Brett, 1991 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - James Brett, 1971-1990 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Leonid I. Brezhnev, undated (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Sidney Brooks, 1984-1998 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - A. Worley Brown, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Hank Brown, 1978-2005 (Box-folder 13: 1-5)
  - University of Colorado (CU-Boulder) President Hank Brown, 2005-2008 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Col. Robert K. Brown, 1986 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Thomas G. Brown, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Allan C. Brownfeld, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Zbigniew Brzezinski, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - William F. Buckley, 1967-1991 (Box-folder 14: 5-6)
  - Vladimir Bukovsky, 1991-2006 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Joseph J. Bulik, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - George Bush, 1989-2004 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Bush administration, 1980-2003 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Bush 2004 campaign (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Chancellor Richard Byyny, CU, 1997 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - CU Chancellor search, 2006 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - William Calder III, 1986-2006 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Glenn Campbell, Hoover Institution, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Russ Campbell, 1989 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Boulder Camera, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Campus Coalition for Democracy, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Cindy Carlisle, 2006 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - Jen Carrigan, 1981 (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - Honorable James E. Carter, Jr., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Bob Carlone, 2005 (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Political cartoons, 1980-1991 (Box-folder 15: 15-16)
  - Center for Science, Technology and Political Thought, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Antonia Chayes, 1980 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - China, 1998 (Box-folder 15: 19)
  - Free China, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
  - Adam Cioch, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Claudio Cioffi-Revilla, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Gary Clark, 2001 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Stephen Cohen, 1987 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Ralph Cole, 1981 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - College Republicans, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Colorado Daily, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Colorado Daily, Suit Total Learning Environment, 1999 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Colorado Daily bankruptcy, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Mary Frances Holloway Combs, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Jim and Jennie Conant, 2005 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Grover Coors, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Holly Coors, 1981-2001 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Joseph Coors, 1966-2002 (Box-folder 16: 16-17)
  - William Coors, 1988-2004 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - James Corbirdge, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 17: 2-3)
  - Christopher Cox, 2006 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Colorado University Events Board, 1986 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Colorado University (CU), 2006 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - CU football scandal, 2004 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Cuba, undated (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Delta Airlines, 1993 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - Tadeusz Deszkiewicz, 2001 (Box-folder 17: 10)
    Letter in Polish.
  - Peter Dietze, 1992 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Philip Dimictrov, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 17: 12)
    Includes one CD-ROM.
  - Philip DiStefano, 1991-1998 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Paul Dirae, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 17: 14)
  - Peter H. Dominic, 1962 (Box-folder 17: 15)
  - Dissident speakers, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 17: 16)
  - Ann Donnelly, 1986-2007 (Box-folder 17: 17)
  - Ann Donnelly, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 18: 1-6)
  - Bill Duff, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Dennis Dunn, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Sue Dwight, 2008 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - Kazimierz Dzlewanowski, 1990 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Bruce Ekstrand, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Professor Ilona E. Ellinger, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Ward Elliott, 1971 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - William Yandell Elliott, 1973-2005 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - John Erickson, 1972 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - T. Hara Tzavella-Evjen, 1990-2005 (Box-folder 19: 6-7)
  - Hal Evjen, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Bob Ewegan, 2005 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - Julio Fernandez, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - Jeffrey Fieger, CU President Search, 1996-2006 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Tammy Fitzgerald, 2009 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - Gerald Ford, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Tim Foster, 2001 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Ben Franklin, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 19: 15)
  - Mindy Franklin, 1988 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - Freedom of Information Act, letter to Ashcroft, 2004 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Freedoms Foundation, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Martha Frey, 1992 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - David Funderbark, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Pamela Gammans, 2009 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Dr. John Gargaro, 2005 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Sender Garlin, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Gay and lesbian material, 1995 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Bill and Roseanne Garnsey, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Andrzei Gelberg, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Ahmad Ghorewhi, 1966-2007 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - Adam Glapinski, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Sir John Glubb, 1969-1986 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Vicki Godbey, 1999-2005 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Clippings, 1962-1978 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Mikhail Gorbachev, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - General Daniel O. Graham, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Bill Gray, 1979-2004 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Phil Gramm, 1991 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Dan Green, 1971 (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Greenburg, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Hamilton Gregg, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Joan Greir, 1993 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Sir Eldon Griffiths, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Petro Grigorenko, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Erwin N. Griswold, 1974-1993 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - Hanna Gronkiewicz-Waltz, 1993 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Michal Gutowski (Box-folder 22: 7)
    Article in Polish.
  - Gutwirth, 1958-1968 (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Alexander Haig, 1978-2001 (Box-folder 22: 9-10)
  - Kirk Hamm, 2002 (Box-folder 22: 11)
  - Anthony Harrigan, 1980-2004 (Box-folder 22: 12)
  - Anthony Harrigan, 1980-2004 (Box-folder 22: 13)
  - Anthony Harrigan, 1979-2004 (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
  - Frank Emerson Harris, 1970-1994 (Box-folder 23: 3-4)
  - Harvard reunion, 1991, 2001 (Box-folder 23: 5-6)
  - Felice Haskel, 1981 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Edward Haugland, 2005-2008 (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - Vclav Havel, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - S. I. Hayakawa, 1969 and after (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - David Hawkins, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Paryur Hayrikyan, 1991 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Dr. Zahi Hawass, 1993 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Linnea Heiny, 2000 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Jesse Helms, 1982 (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - Gustav Herling-Gridzinski, 2000 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Jimmie Heuga, 1989-1999 (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - Sidney Hook, 1959-1985 (Box-folder 24: 10-11)
  - J. Edgar Hoover, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 24: 12)
  - Hoover Institution, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 24: 13)
  - Dr. Gabor Havanyc, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 24: 14)
  - Alex Hunter, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - INTERDOC, 1974 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - International Platform Association, 1989 (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Elzbieta Isakiewicz, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Howard Janssen, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Gordon Johnson, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Walter J. Judd, 1950-1999 (Box-folder 25: 7-9)
  - Judd book, thank you letters, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Stefan Jurczak, 1997 (Box-folder 25: 11)
  - Ryszard Kaczorowski, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Ojars Kalnins, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - Guy Kelley, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - George Kennedy, 1992 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Walter Kennedy, 2002 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Dr. Stepan Khmara, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 26: 6)
  - Robe Maghrabi, 1988 (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Valentyn Moroz, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - William C. Mott, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Paul Murphy, 1971-2005 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - John Nelson, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - Quigg Newton, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - Nguyen Cao Ky, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Thomas Nichols, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - Richard Nixon, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - W.W. Norton, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Andrzej Nowak, 2001 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Tadeusz Nowakowski, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Peter K. Ogloblin, 1958-2006 (Box-folder 27: 7-9)
  - Jan Olszewski, 1996-2006 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - Boleslaw Orlowski, 2003-2008 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Governor Owens, 2003-2008 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Michael S. Pap, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Roderick Park, 1994 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Dave Parker, 2006 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Mary Ann Pauken, 1988 (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - Jay Peake, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  - Z. A. Pelezynski, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - Jack Penn, 1972-2007 (Box-folder 28: 7-8)
  - Bill Peterson, 1964 (Box-folder 28: 9)
  - Kien Pham, 1986 (Box-folder 28: 10)
  - Philadelphia Society, 1977 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Herb Philbrick, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 28: 12)
  - Ogman Raytchev Pishev, Ambassador of Bulgaria, 1993 (Box-folder 28: 13)
  - Norman Podhoretz, 1986 (Box-folder 28: 14)
  - Trip to Poland, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 28: 15)
  - Poland, 1970-1992 (Box-folder 28: 16)
  - Polish Consul General, 2001 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Letters from Poles, 1979-2001 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Polish materials, 1981-2004 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Steve Polidori, 2008 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Estanio Potocki, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - George Powell, 1995 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Presidential and Regents Scholars, 1972 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Presidential Search Committee, 1999 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - Ksawery Pruszynski, 2007 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Pulitzer Prize, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 29: 10)
  - Rubin Rabinovitz, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - Arthur Randall, 1990 (Box-folder 29: 12)
  - Roland Rautenstraus, 1997 (Box-folder 29: 13)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1967-1983 (Box-folder 30: 1-2)
    Correspondence and newspaper clippings regarding Ronald Reagan.
  - Reagan presidential campaign, 1980 (Box-folder 30: 3)
    Certificate, articles and correspondence.
  - Board of Regents from University of Colorado, 1987-2006 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    Correspondence, newspaper clippings, and documents.
  - William A. Renee correspondence, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Republican Party, Old, newspaper and magazine clippings, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - Jean-Francois Revel (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - James Robb, 1989 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Shari Robertson, 1981 (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - George Roche, 1967-1999 (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - Antoni Rogozinski, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 30: 11)
    In Polish.
  - Mike Rosen correspondence, 1990-2008 (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - A. M. Rosenthal correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Watt W. Rostow correspondence, 1967-1985 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Edward Rowney, 1990-2005 (Box-folder 31: 3)